<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Notes on Jesse Krijthe</title>
    <link>https://www.jessekrijthe.com/categories/Machine-Learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jesse Krijthe</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>jkrijthe@gmail.com (Jesse Krijthe)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>jkrijthe@gmail.com (Jesse Krijthe)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.jessekrijthe.com/categories/Machine-Learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PhD Defense</title>
      <link>https://www.jessekrijthe.com/articles/phd-defense/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>jkrijthe@gmail.com (Jesse Krijthe)</author>
      <guid>https://www.jessekrijthe.com/articles/phd-defense/</guid>
      <description>I defended my PhD thesis! The thesis &amp;ldquo;Robust Semi-supervised Learning: Projections, Limits &amp;amp; Constraints&amp;rdquo; is about exploring the limits of the guarantees one can give for whether a semi-supervised learner will outperform its supervised counterpart. In other words: the limits of the usefulness of additional unlabeled data in a supervised learning setting.
While it seems to make sense you would want such guarantees before using semi-supervised methods to incorporate unlabeled data into the learning process, we show that without additional assumptions, for many supervised learners, semi-supervised alternatives with strict non-degradation guarantees can not be constructed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Favourite Work at ICML 2015</title>
      <link>https://www.jessekrijthe.com/articles/icml2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 13:09:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>jkrijthe@gmail.com (Jesse Krijthe)</author>
      <guid>https://www.jessekrijthe.com/articles/icml2015/</guid>
      <description>This post is just to remind myself of some of my favourite posters/presentations that I saw while attending ICML. I have undoubtably missed a lot of interesting stuff. If you have any particular suggestions, please let me know!
The Fundamental Incompatibility of Scalable Hamiltonian Monte Carlo and Naive Data Subsampling Michael Betancourt I liked the topic and the kind of analysis and I especially liked his clear style of presentation. Moreover, there was quite a lively discussion about whether this incompatibility is actually a problem, or whether it focussed too much on only the bias that is introduced by naive subsampling.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>